<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
    <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144</link>
    <description>
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;This is a companion discussion topic for the original entry at &lt;a href=&quot;https://curi.us/2607-kpop-demon-hunters&quot;&gt;https://curi.us/2607-kpop-demon-hunters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:40:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Elliot Temple</category>
    <atom:link href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ActiveMind]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous105" data-post="28" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/8797f3/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous105:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Is <em>We the Living</em> also short?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>For my physical copies with roughly same font size and page size, WTL is 443 pages and FH is 727 pages.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous105" data-post="26" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/8797f3/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous105:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I also think storytelling often follows guidelines about when it is or isn’t a good idea to have a bleak unhappy ending.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This depends on the philosophical world view of the author. If they hold the malevolent universe premise then it’s inverted; tragic endings are the default and happy endings require justification.</p>
<p>That applies mostly just for intellectual fiction. With such fiction you kind of make a trade off where you learn something about the human condition or society but have to get sad over the tragedy. For popular fiction the goal is more to make it enjoyable than to make it didactic.</p>
<p>Surely there are people who enjoy sad stories without much philosophical substance in them, but I think they’re a minority. Though I can think up vague examples of people saying “the ending was so sad!” implying it was good without talking about what it teaches you. So maybe I’m underestimating how much people like sad endings.</p>
<p>I can imagine that people like fiction that makes them feel <em>something</em>. Boring fiction that spark no emotions is worse than those that spark negative feelings, all else being equal.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous105" data-post="26" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/8797f3/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous105:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I haven’t read <em>We the Living</em> but my understanding is that it’s more of a true dystopian story. So that would track.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>For Rand, the justification for the tragic ending in WtL is not realism, but the philosophical meaning it implies about collectivism. She talks about this in the end of <em>The Art of Fiction</em>.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/31</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-31</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[anonymous105]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Got it.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous105" data-post="28" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/8797f3/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous105:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Or I got them confused in my head and conflated them into one short dystopian book with a bleak ending.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I must have done this then. They morphed into a single book in my mind.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/30</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-30</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous105" data-post="28" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/8797f3/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous105:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Is <em>We the Living</em> also short?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>no</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous105" data-post="28" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/8797f3/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous105:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Does <em>Anthem</em> have a bleak ending?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>no</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/29</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 21:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-29</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[anonymous105]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Oh, oops! I was absolutely confusing <em>We the Living</em> with <em>Anthem</em>. <em>Anthem</em> is the short dystopia.</p>
<p>Is <em>We the Living</em> also short? Does <em>Anthem</em> have a bleak ending?</p>
<p>Guessing I wasn’t thinking of <em>We the Living</em> at all at any point and was only ever thinking of <em>Anthem</em> by mistake. Or I got them confused in my head and conflated them into one short dystopian book with a bleak ending. I have not read either of them.</p>
<p>I think my broader comments still stand. Also, realistic historical dramas (whether fiction or not) are another genre that often have very bleak endings regardless of the story’s length. Depending on what era of history, at least. I think this makes sense… History can be very bleak, and people often know the broad strokes of the bleak historical period before they start the story. Both of those facts contribute to it being a more accepted type of ending.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/28</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-28</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous105" data-post="26" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/8797f3/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous105:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I haven’t read <em>We the Living</em> but my understanding is that it’s more of a true dystopian story.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>No. Dystopia means:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>an imagined state or society in which there is great suffering or injustice, typically one that is totalitarian or post-apocalyptic.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>We the Living</em> is set in communist Russia. It’s realistic. It’s not like <em>1984</em> which tries to imagine a hypothetical society. Rand’s true dystopian book is <em>Anthem</em>, which is set in a hypothetical communist society which is worse than the USSR. FYI, <em>Anthem</em> is short and you could read it in one sitting.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/27</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-27</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[anonymous105]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Elliot" data-post="20" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>If you watch TV shows, e.g. police procedurals, things tend to wrap up positively in under an hour, often with minimal adversity. Like the adversity is they had to go find some more evidence and their boss doubted them in the middle. Medical drama TV shows often follow the same structure.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Depends a lot on the show. Sometimes police procedurals also include stuff like protagonists getting into gunfights, which would be adversity in real life but are often portrayed as mostly just thrilling and badass.</p>
<p>But in general I mostly had long form stories such as novels and movies in mind. Serialized shows often don’t have the same adversity <em>every episode</em> but they might have the protagonists face some serious adversity periodically, e.g. season finales or dramatic 2-part episodes.</p>
<p>Most episodes of House he is just snarky and the patient is the one facing adversity, but every so often he ends up in prison or has a traumatic drug induced hallucination or whatever. If you look at the totality of any given show’s run, most of them do have genuine non-trivial adversity pop up at least a couple times. But again I do agree it varies based on genre, and some genres are fairly low in adversity.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Elliot" data-post="20" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Atlas Shrugged</em> and <em>The Fountainhead</em> are more in line with highly respected books for having more adversity, drama, ups and downs, etc. It’s different than a lot of plotlines you’d see with Superman, Star Trek, Law and Order, fanfiction.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Yeah, I agree. I did intend to imply this with this line (bold added):</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Many protagonists in <strong>successful</strong> fiction experience very real, serious setbacks.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You mentioned Star Trek… while many individual episodes may be fairly low stakes, over the course of their runs (mostly thinking of the ones I know well, from the 90s; TNG, DS9, VOY) there is a lot of really serious adversity! Characters are tortured, imprisoned, experimented on, stranded in hostile environments for extended periods, injured in critical condition, die, lose loved ones, face major moral dilemmas that challenge their beliefs, etc.</p>
<p>I have become a much bigger fan of Star Trek after rewatching it recently, I think overall it does this sort of thing better than many other examples of serialized fiction (Law and Order, etc.) where I agree with you more.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Elliot" data-post="20" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>If you don’t think AS and FH show success as hard, then do any stories (particularly about realistic scenarios, not zombie apocalypses)?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>No, I do think FH shows success as hard within the story. I was just saying that because it has a happy ending for the protagonist I think a lot of people can come away from it feeling good. And that can extend into feeling empowered, like they can do it too, like maybe it’s not <em>that</em> hard, etc.</p>
<p>Some of these reactions are probably good, but my guess is that they can also lead to overconfidence. This feels like a classic difficult problem between confidence and overconfidence. You don’t want people to feel demoralized and hopeless, but it’s also not good if they get arrogant and sloppy.</p>
<p>I don’t really have a solution to that problem. To the extent I don’t think a solution to it is present in Rand’s fiction, I don’t think that’s her fault. It’s not really the problem she was trying to solve anyway.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Elliot" data-post="20" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>And <em>We the Living</em> doesn’t have a good ending despite having a deserving hero.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Yeah I have not read that but I am aware of it and was pretty sure that it had a bleak ending. I only mentioned FH because that’s the only one I remembered well and was pretty confident about.</p>
<p>I also think storytelling often follows guidelines about when it is or isn’t a good idea to have a bleak unhappy ending. Some genres and types of stories can more reliably get away with bleak endings.</p>
<p>Dystopian stories are a good example. AS &amp; FH have elements of dystopianism in them but I think they are more like big dramas. I haven’t read <em>We the Living</em> but my  understanding is that it’s more of a true dystopian story. So that would track.</p>
<p>Also, I have a theory that short stories can get away with bleak endings more reliably than long form stories. Not to say long form stories don’t have bleak endings sometimes. But I think it’s much more common in short stories. I have noticed this a lot in Science Fiction. Short speculative Sci-Fi is often bleak, dystopian, horrific, or otherwise has sad/bad endings. Long form Sci-Fi, even if it is overall bleak, will usually have some element of hope in the ending.</p>
<p>My guess for why this is: Bleak endings can leave readers feeling bad. But the longer time you’ve spent with the protagonists, the more emotionally invested you are, the worse it can end up feeling. For shorter stories, the bleak ending can be sad but the thought-provoking and challenging elements can be interesting enough to be the primary thing the reader thinks about. For long stories, it can be harder to appreciate that stuff if the ending of the story is too bleak and all of the characters the reader grew attached to end the story in a horrible place.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/26</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-26</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ActiveMind]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="ActiveMind" data-post="24" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/activemind/48/5560_2.png" class="avatar"> ActiveMind:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Some people think that only tragic endings are respectable and that happy endings are naive. Which is because they hold the malevolent universe premise and believe that life is fundamentally tragic.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Some of them would look down upon happy endings as “feel good stories”, whereas real art, they would say, is supposed to challenge you, to make you uncomfortable.</p>
<p>Rand’s books aren’t about making you feel good, instead their effect should be to give you spiritual fuel and inspire you to pursue values in life. Her books <em>do</em> challenge you. They challenge you to strive for moral perfection and settling for nothing less. “Feel good stories” would tell you that you’re okay as you are and that you need to change nothing about yourself.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/25</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 02:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-25</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ActiveMind]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Elliot" data-post="20" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Atlas Shrugged</em> and <em>The Fountainhead</em> are more in line with highly respected books for having more adversity, drama, ups and downs, etc.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Some people think that only tragic endings are respectable and that happy endings are naive. Which is because they hold the malevolent universe premise and believe that life is fundamentally tragic.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Elliot" data-post="20" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>And <em>We the Living</em> doesn’t have a good ending despite having a deserving hero.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Spoilers for <em>We the Living</em> and <em>1984</em>:</p>
<div class="spoiler"><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/24">spoiler</a></div>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/24</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 02:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-24</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jarrod]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Eternity" data-post="15" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/eternity/48/5535_2.png" class="avatar"> Eternity:</div>
<blockquote>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Apricus" data-post="4" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/apricus/48/855_2.png" class="avatar"> Apricus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>It might also be that movies and media in general make it seem easier to be nice than it actually is in real life. Perhaps it idealizes or romanticizes the actual execution of those values.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>~yeah. I think media makes things feel easier than they are. reading something like Atlas Shrugged or The Fountainhead makes having integrity and being rational easy. I don’t think Rand wrote it in a way that said their easy. But something about reading about it makes it feel easy.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I think that Apricus has a good point.</p>
<p>I think that reading a stylized narration of a character’s actions can make it feel much clearer what the right and wrong decisions are. It can create a sense of moral clarity.</p>
<p>It’d be like the difference between reading about a character who wastes time on Facebook instead of studying for an impending exam… versus actually being a person IRL who spends time on Facebook instead of studying.</p>
<p>I think when you read about someone else doing it, it can feel more obvious when they’re making a mistake. Besides, authors often write in a slanted/stylized sort of way that makes it clearer what the right and wrong decisions are.</p>
<p>(Also, viewing one’s own actions through someone else’s perspective can have the same effect. E.g., having a boss looking over one’s shoulder can make one more acutely aware of when one is doing something subpar.)</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Elliot" data-post="22" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Do you feel that way with other fiction? Detective stuff? Superhero stuff? Outer space stuff? Doctors saving patients?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I don’t think so. Perhaps because being a detective, astronaut, or doctor requires skills that I don’t have (and it’s intuitively obvious to me that I don’t have those skills).</p>
<p>I don’t think I could be as good of a detective as Hercule Poirot or Sherlock Holmes. (At least not without decades of practice. And even then, I’d probably still fail to reach their skill level.)</p>
<p>Maybe people view moral knowledge/skill as easier and more accessible than technical skill. Perhaps people feel that it’s easier to become a hero than a brain surgeon.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/23</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 01:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-23</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Do you feel that way with other fiction? Detective stuff? Superhero stuff? Outer space stuff? Doctors saving patients?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/22</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 23:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-22</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Eternity]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Elliot" data-post="18" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>There is media where everything always works out for the protagonist and their setbacks are only superficial. But Rand’s books aren’t like that.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I agree. I was just saying that something about reading makes things feel easy. I wasn’t talking about how the setbacks the characters face per se. Its more so something about just reading it makes it feel easier to achieve than it actually is. Like, idk, when Rearden refuses to work with the government and instead chooses to fight the issue with the regulation in court (I hope I’m remembering that correctly). Do I think I can as easily make decisions as Rearden makes, or any of the other protagonists in Miss Reardens books? No, but something about reading those actions makes it feel like something I can do. Its like by reading I felt like I did it.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/21</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 22:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-21</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>If you watch TV shows, e.g. police procedurals, things tend to wrap up positively in under an hour, often with minimal adversity. Like the adversity is they had to go find some more evidence and their boss doubted them in the middle. Medical drama TV shows often follow the same structure.</p>
<p><em>Atlas Shrugged</em> and <em>The Fountainhead</em> are more in line with highly respected books for having more adversity, drama, ups and downs, etc. It’s different than a lot of plotlines you’d see with Superman, Star Trek, Law and Order, fanfiction. If you don’t think AS and FH show success as hard, then do any stories (particularly about realistic scenarios, not zombie apocalypses)?</p>
<p>And <em>We the Living</em> doesn’t have a good ending despite having a deserving hero.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/20</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 20:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-20</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[anonymous105]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Elliot" data-post="18" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>There is media where everything always works out for the protagonist and their setbacks are only superficial. But Rand’s books aren’t like that.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>There’s also media where everything works out for the protagonist <strong>in the end</strong>, and their setbacks are only <strong>temporary</strong>. I think at least Fountainhead is like this — Roark ends the book in a triumphant way, his life is going well, he is doing architecture and he got the girl.</p>
<p>That is meaningfully different from the setbacks being <strong>superficial</strong>. Many protagonists in successful fiction experience very real, serious setbacks. They get badly injured, or lose their job, or have their reputation smeared, or have close friends die, or get their heart broken, etc. But in most fiction, the protagonist overcomes the setbacks and ends the story in a triumphant way.</p>
<p>My guess would be the exceptions in either direction — the story ending sadly with the setbacks having broken the protagonist, or the story being an easy experience where most stuff just works out with minimal problems for the protagonist — aren’t uncommon but might be a relative minority. Though it varies some across genres, too.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Apricus" data-post="4" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/apricus/48/855_2.png" class="avatar"> Apricus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>It might also be that movies and media in general make it seem easier to be nice than it actually is in real life. Perhaps it idealizes or romanticizes the actual execution of those values.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I wonder if this feeling might occur even if the setbacks are serious but temporary. Not just when the setbacks are superficial/trivial.</p>
<p>Because by the end of the story things worked out okay. People often are biased to most remember their feeling at the end of a story rather than how they felt throughout it (e.g. when the hero was at their lowest). So if things worked out in the end, I wouldn’t be surprised if many people come away from that feeling like it wasn’t all that bad and they, too, could have done what the protagonist did.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/19</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-19</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Eternity" data-post="15" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/eternity/48/5535_2.png" class="avatar"> Eternity:</div>
<blockquote>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Apricus" data-post="4" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/apricus/48/855_2.png" class="avatar"> Apricus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>It might also be that movies and media in general make it seem easier to be nice than it actually is in real life. Perhaps it idealizes or romanticizes the actual execution of those values.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>~yeah. I think media makes things feel easier than they are. reading something like Atlas Shrugged or The Fountainhead makes having integrity and being rational easy. I don’t think Rand wrote it in a way that said their easy. But something about reading about it makes it feel easy.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Rand made multiple attempts to present it as hard. Roark closed his architecture office and worked as a manual laborer. Dagny quit her job at the railroad and had a rough time at the cabin – and then returned to the railroad against the advice of Galt and others. Kira had it even harder.</p>
<p>There is media where everything always works out for the protagonist and their setbacks are only superficial. But Rand’s books aren’t like that.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/18</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-18</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[anonymous105]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Eternity" data-post="13" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/eternity/48/5535_2.png" class="avatar"> Eternity:</div>
<blockquote>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous45" data-post="3" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/a87d85/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous45:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>LoLE dynamics</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>What’s that? I tried googling it. Sadge.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>It can be helpful to append “acronym” when googling an unfamiliar set of initials like that. Just googling “lole” you get a ton of stuff for a clothing brand. But if you add the word acronym to the search it immediately finds Law of Least Effort.</p>
<p>Still good to ask if you don’t know, since maybe Anon45 was referring to some other identical acronym. Good to clarify so you know for sure.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/17</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-17</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Eternity]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous45" data-post="14" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/a87d85/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous45:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Law of Least Effort. Basically that people convey being high up in a social hierarchy by appearing as though they don’t put much effort in to things. Basically, stuff you do looks cooler.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Ahh. Ok. I’m kind of aware of what that is. Wasn’t used to seeing it abbreviated.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous45" data-post="14" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/a87d85/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous45:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>This query is useful: <code>site:curi.us LoLE</code> for any CF specific terms/ideas. (I don’t think LoLE is CF specific, but searching <a href="http://curi.us">curi.us</a> is useful in this case)</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I didn’t know you can search like that. Thats neat. Thanks!</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/16</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 03:36:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-16</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Eternity]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Apricus" data-post="4" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/apricus/48/855_2.png" class="avatar"> Apricus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Maybe there’s a gap between the girl’s understanding of the values in the movie vs. the decisions she faces in real life?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Maybe? I think people in general struggle to match values they talk about. This kind of reminds of me something related to Rand. I think Peikoff mentioned how when Atlas Shrugged was first published. He and others (and maybe Rand?) thought the world would get better fast because of the convincingness of Atlas Shrugged. Instead people read it, some (maybe a lot, idk) liked it, said they agreed with it, and changed pmuch nothing on their lives.</p>
<p>I wonder if it has something to do with something else I’ve heard of before (I think from Rand?): the church mentality (or smth like that). People care about their values only at like important times. Not in their general lives. You go to church and you’ll do charity and stuff. The rest of the week you’re your average self.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Apricus" data-post="4" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/apricus/48/855_2.png" class="avatar"> Apricus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>It might also be that movies and media in general make it seem easier to be nice than it actually is in real life. Perhaps it idealizes or romanticizes the actual execution of those values.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>~yeah. I think media makes things feel easier than they are. reading something like Atlas Shrugged or The Fountainhead makes having integrity and being rational easy. I don’t think Rand wrote it in a way that said their easy. But something about reading about it makes it feel easy.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/15</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 03:35:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-15</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[anonymous45]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Eternity" data-post="13" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/eternity/48/5535_2.png" class="avatar"> Eternity:</div>
<blockquote>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous45" data-post="3" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/a87d85/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous45:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>LoLE dynamics</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>What’s that? I tried googling it. Sadge.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Law of Least Effort. Basically that people convey being high up in a social hierarchy by appearing as though they don’t put much effort in to things. Basically, stuff you do looks cooler.</p>
<p>This query is useful: <code>site:curi.us LoLE</code> for any CF specific terms/ideas. (I don’t think LoLE is CF specific, but searching <a href="http://curi.us">curi.us</a> is useful in this case)</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/14</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 03:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-14</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Eternity]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous45" data-post="3" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/a87d85/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous45:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>LoLE dynamics</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>What’s that? I tried googling it. Sadge.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous45" data-post="3" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/a87d85/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous45:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>One thing I wonder about is how much people pick up on, respond to, or internalize less explicit parts of films like this. If people subconsciously respond less to the explicit parts and more to the implicit parts, it might explain why media that moralizes is not particularly effective.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I could be reading this wrong. Uhh. Oh. Hmm.</p>
<p>Are you saying that the moralizing is explicit in films like this? I think what you say makes sense. I kinda just assumed that a lot of the stuff Elliot mentioned is implicit. Woops. I just assumed they wanted to make a movie and the themes are whatever to them. The fun movie takes priority and then they add themes and stuff. Hope that makes sense?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/13</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 03:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-13</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Dface]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Most of these thoughts I think are half-baked. I feel like im getting somewhere with them but I’m missing the bigger picture:</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Elliot" data-post="1" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Popularity is, to some extent, a zero sum game. There is a limited amount of attention that people can pay to others. Some people getting a lot of attention doesn’t increase the total amount of attention available. Attention is a scarce resource.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I’m thinking you say “to some extent” cuz there may be some exceptions. I have to look up what to some extent means and figure why you said it.</p>
<p>I think since popularity has to do with being paid attention to and being praised or liked or whatever, people either pay attention to you or not. Maybe sometimes one person pays more attention to others and the resource goes higher? Idk, I think looking at the meaning of what popularity is may say why you say “to some extent.” I don’t think looking that up makes a whole lot of difference to your point tho.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Elliot" data-post="1" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>So of course people aren’t great at actually being nice and accepting in the way KDH says to. Even in KDH itself, there are conflicting themes. KDH normalizes a small number of people being ultra-popular while ignoring that some people in the huge audience can also sing well but will never get similar recognition for their talent. And either that’s unfair or else the less popular people have less merit in which case being dismissive of them in some ways is valid.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>You say “And either that’s unfair” cuz why do people with as much merit not get popular too, I think. Why do a small number of people have to be ultra-popular? Why not just popular? Have the popularity go around more.</p>
<p>And I think you say “And either that’s unfair or else” cuz if it isn’t unfair then it’s the case I think that the less popular people have less merit. I don’t know how less popular people are seen as having less merit if they can sing just as well.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Elliot" data-post="1" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>KDH normalizes being accepting of flaws from ultra-popular people. It illustrates that. It doesn’t illustrate any regular fans in the crowd having flaws and being accepted anyway. It doesn’t even illustrate people in the crowd with no notable flaws being important, interesting or talented, or getting much attention.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>It’s interesting how the movie may serve to be beneficial to very popular people. Like, by logic and how not everybody can be popular, people will be dismissed and treated intolerably. That makes me think there’s not a lot of rational thinking going into making these kinds of movies, and that that can cause harm I guess. I say “I guess” cuz I don’t want to just say something causes harm readily, I don’t know a lot about what causes others harm.</p>
<p>For the third sentence of the quote above:</p>
<p>I think if someone saw that as a point in a casual convo, they would respond: ‘Why them? It’s not about them?’ Or ‘That doesn’t make sense. You’re overthinking the movie’ or ‘I don’t see how that all connects, why are you bringing up regular fans being the center of the story?’ Or why pay attention to those average joes??? KDH is so likeable.’</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Elliot" data-post="1" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>KDH shows a main character, who is extremely talented and popular, having anxiety. I think it’s partly meant to normalize such struggles for everyone.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Oh, she’s already popular? I think her being popular just makes it easier to illustrate the theme. I think it’s harder to show how an unpopular person is good enough. I think that’s cuz there is truth to how much merit doesn’t matter to being popular. You could be a really good singer but not be liked. Idk</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Elliot" data-post="1" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Even those people you look up to struggle. But then it turns out she is good enough, is enough, didn’t need to have so much anxiety. OK but does that apply to a high school student with no fans, no talents, no skills, no direction in life, no special merit at anything? Does it apply to a young adult with a mundane job? Is everyone already good enough, or just impressive people?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>That’s where things don’t make sense. Like, I don’t think the movie or the people who made the movie know what’s good enough in somebody. Cuz why not apply that to show how everyone is good enough? Maybe if the viewer just doesn’t overthink their anxiety they can find that they are a really good singer. Ok, what about the people who are good enough at singing high notes, but need to work on having a more consistent tone or sing low notes or soemthing(idk a lot about music). That’s the thing, I don’t think people know what success is, like how does look like for someone who isn’t super popular or doesn’t want to be. How does success look like for them?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/12</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 02:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-12</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Dface]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Elliot" data-post="1" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>They don’t have to be mean to anyone, but not everyone can be super popular like the pop star heroes of KDH.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>When you say people don’t have to be mean to anyone, does “have” refer to the limited time and attention that they have? Just cuz they have limited time and attention, it doesn’t mean they have to be mean to anyone.</p>
<p>Because people are mean anyways, that’s the difficulty you were talking about in the next sentence? Idk</p>
<p>I see there’s a “but” in the quote above, but idk what’s being contrasted. Does “They don’t have to be mean to anyone” mean people don’t have to be intolerant of anyone?</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Elliot" data-post="1" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>This difficulty may explain some of the shortcomings in people’s tolerance.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Is the difficulty that people are actually being mean when they don’t have to? Or that people are intolerant of others when they don’t have to? Or is the difficulty something that is hard to understand? Like, those that view the theme as saying to be nice to everyone, etc. are being unrealistic. You can’t be nice to everyone. The difficulty is that they are being unrealistic.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Elliot" data-post="1" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I think it’s even connected with violence because being dismissive of people leads to unfamiliarity not respect, which I think does serve to help enable violence.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>The difficulty is connected with violence?</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/11</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-11</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Dface]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Elliot" data-post="1" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>People being different is pretty much the only thing people are dismissed for. What else would you reject someone for?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>So people reject others because they are different.</p>
<p>What’s the difference between rejecting someone and dismissing them? If you’re rejecting someone, you’re dismissing them? I think if you’re rejecting them from something, it’s from like a club or friend group. For dismissing someone, I think if someone is different they could be dismissed from being treated nicely or having a conversation or being taken seriously.</p>
<p>My half-baked thoughts below:</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Elliot" data-post="1" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>If people simply lacked skill at tolerance, you might expect some experts to be great at it. People who study rationality or psychology might excel at it. But I don’t think they do.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I don’t think they do either. I think a person that studies rationality or psychology doesn’t ecxcel at tolereance cuz what are they studying to be tolerant?</p>
<p>I’m thinking at least in the fields of rationality it’s hard to understand how to get better at tolerance. I think studying something like CF can help with learning to be more tolerant. I think learning resolving conflicts of ideas can help one be more tolerant cuz they take the other side of an argument more into consideration and don’t just shut them down in favor of their idea. But I also think you have to make the connection to be tolerant to others. Idk what psychology or rationality helps with that? I haven’t really researched so there might be some examples. But how does rationality stuff and psychology have people excel at tolerance? I think people learn to be tolerant on their own through their own reasoning and knowledge.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Elliot" data-post="1" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/elliot/48/14_2.png" class="avatar"> Elliot:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Maybe intellectuals are better than average at not being racist, but I’m not sure about that either. Some clever people end up kind of racist because they’re impressed by clever, logical arguments for racism-adjacent ideas, and they arrogantly think they’re just being scientific or something, but actually they’re pretty racist in a way that a less intellectual person might avoid.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>The question I have is what are they studying to help them not be racist? I think being tolerant is a boundary based thing that people remind each other of. Like, it’s not really explained well, and so people don’t understand how it works in situations where they’re actually being racist.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/10</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 09:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-10</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="anonymous105" data-post="8" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/8797f3/48.png" class="avatar"> anonymous105:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Of course you’re tolerant of flaws and differences. But you can’t be tolerant of demons, obviously. You are tolerant of the flaws of the people you care about, people in your tribe. Because you’re a good person.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Yeah I noticed the way they casually kill demons, while smiling, was very problematic if you consider the demons in terms of being heretics or enemy soldiers in wars.</p>
<p>Related to attitudes to demons: <span class="spoiler"><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/9">spoiler</a></span></p>
<p>Unrelated, the demon hunters are drawn anorexic with video game proportions but shown eating like they aren’t anorexic, which is also problematic.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/9</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-9</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[anonymous105]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Apricus" data-post="4" data-topic="2144">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="24" height="24" src="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/user_avatar/discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/apricus/48/855_2.png" class="avatar"> Apricus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Why do people like a movie that espouses values that go against how they actually behave?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I think this is broadly true for most people across most movie genres. It is not specific to the themes in KPop Demon Hunters (not saying you or Elliot claimed it was).</p>
<p>There are entire <strong>genres</strong> of films that espouse values that the audience do not live.</p>
<p>For example, heroic action movies where one person is willing to stand up against injustice/evil/crime/violence, or even grayer action movies where one person is willing to go to extraordinary lengths to rescue someone/get vengeance/etc.</p>
<p>People love these movies, but most people don’t live values like that. Most people don’t stand up for their values or principles or even their loved ones to that extent. Most people do not experience the extreme scenarios in these stories, but they often don’t even stand up for this stuff to a much less extreme extent that would be relevant in their life.</p>
<p>Another example: There are detective stories where the detective is obsessed with solving a mystery and finding the truth. They keep pursuing the truth, come into conflict with superiors, and reject convenient falsehoods until they find the real answer. But most people don’t behave that way. Most cops don’t, but also just applied to regular life most people do not try to find truthful answers to problems with that kind of dedication.</p>
<p>Overall my guess is that a majority of films (and stories in general) promote values that the average viewer/fan of the film fails to live up to.</p>
<p>Why? I don’t really know, but I have some guesses.</p>
<p>Fictional stories are often pretty good at creating dramatic, extreme scenarios. These may be totally unrealistic, or they might be realistic but unusual in that most people don’t experience something quite as extreme. They do this for many reasons. A big one is: It’s more exciting and thus captures attention better.</p>
<p>But another reason is that those scenarios can make conflicts and problems <strong>clearer</strong>. Real life can be messy and confusing. Your personal biases and emotions can get in the way. In fiction, it is often easier to tell what’s going on. Stuff like… Who is the bad guy. Who has positive motives, who is misguided, who is evil. What are the stakes.</p>
<p>When it isn’t your life, and when so many of the variables are more clearly demonstrated in the story, it can be a lot easier to understand which principles are good and which are bad. But once the story ends and you go back to your real life, it may not be so easy to translate the same ideas. You aren’t a neutral observer. To you, everyone who fucks you over feels like the bad guy, with evil motives. Watching a movie you could e.g. recognize that a bad guy was misguided and deserves a second chance, but in real life you may not be able to see the same things.</p>
<p>Circling this back to KPDH a little… most people like the idea of being tolerant of differences and nice. When it is demonstrated in a film with an exaggerated scenario, it’s relatively easy to see what’s going on and how to be tolerant. The protagonist is nice and cool, so obviously we should be tolerant of her differences.</p>
<p>In real life, things are messy.</p>
<p>Being tolerant of flaws is good, though. And you totally live that value, for example you are tolerant of your dad’s flaw where he says the N word and complains about the Jews controlling the media, because he loves you and he is a good father and grandfather. And you believe being tolerant in general is good, which is why you are so concerned that the younger generation of atheists is so intolerant of Christianity nowadays.</p>
<p>And obviously, being tolerant is not the same thing as being stupid and self-destructive. The Demon Hunters accepted their friend’s flaws but they still killed the evil demons afterwards. They didn’t just welcome the demons into the human world. You know that wouldn’t be tolerant, it would be stupid and suicidal. And likewise, we can’t just welcome in 100 million illegals the way Biden did, that was stupid and suicidal. We have to get rid of them, because they are evil demons poisoning our country, and if that requires sending ICE into cities, suspending due process, putting the demons in camps, and killing people that try to stop us… well, you know that’s necessary to protect ourselves from this invasion.</p>
<p>Of course you’re tolerant of flaws and differences. But you can’t be tolerant of demons, obviously. You are tolerant of the flaws of the people you care about, people in your tribe. Because you’re a good person.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/8</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-8</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KPop Demon Hunters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliot]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I think the theme of niceness, acceptance, tolerance, etc., is very vague. You shouldn’t just give an hour of free attention to anyone who asks for it. You should be somewhat dismissive in some ways. You shouldn’t be violent or yell slurs at people (usually, but self defense can be OK), but you can be cold and mean without doing anything egregious like that. So what ways should you be nice or not? How nice should you be to who? You shouldn’t treat everyone identically. This stuff isn’t specified in any detail by the movie or by any book I know of.</p>
          <p><a href="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144/6</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 05:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">discuss.criticalfallibilism.com-post-2144-6</guid>
        <source url="https://discuss.criticalfallibilism.com/t/kpop-demon-hunters/2144.rss">KPop Demon Hunters</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
